Saw Yee Boon



ah_boon95@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/yee-boon-saw



+6016-6268736



https://www.codebyboon.com

Summary

Previous Position: Application Development Specialist in Accenture Malaysia

Industry: Financial Service

Highest Education: Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering

Years of Experiences: 5 years+ Experience in: Banking, Insurance

I'm an Application Development Specialist with a combined 5 years+ experience of application development with a demonstrated history of working in Financial Services industry (Banking, Insurance). I have helped clients build applications & frameworks in multiple projects, by going through SDLC activities.

Some examples include:

- Building IFRS17 framework for Insurance Company
- CRM system for Banking using Oracle Siebel

Skilled in Solution Architecture, Requirement Gathering & Analysis, Application Development & Release Management, Applications Building & Configuration, Application Maintenance and Application Testing.

Experience

> Application Development Specialist

Accenture

Jun 2022 - May 2023 (1 year)

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Gather requirements for new project & CRs, requirements analysis, and assess the deliverables for the requirements.
- Set delivery priority and scoping of the project with business owner, development team and project owners.
- Application development lead for banking CRM system. Conduct plan and analysis phase, scope management handling and testing process.
- Identify root cause for production issues & providing solutions for business process
- In charge of server monitoring, maintenance for the project as a Technical Architecture
- Make necessary schedule adjustment to meet timely delivery goals.
- In charge of monthly achievement call with clients to ensure the performance is consistent, addressing any challenges/issues with the project.
- Managing and leading a team in deliverables, guiding the team with my knowledge and experiences.

ACCOMPLISHMENT:

- Setting up & Building IFRS17 Framework for Prudential Malaysia.
- Project planning & management, deliverables done for UOB CRM system.
- Managed a team which consists of L3 BAU support & application developer for UOB CRM system.

Application Development Senior Analyst

Accenture

Dec 2019 - May 2022 (2 years 6 months)

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Gather requirements for new CRs, analyze business requirements, and assess the deliverables for the requirements in both Bank and Insurance company.
- Identify root cause for production issues & providing solutions for business process using Informix, perform data patching activities using SQL to fix the production issues.
- Leading a team consisting of L3 BAU support for Insurance client.
- Consulted Bank in Vietnam in baselining their current operations, procedures and applications performances; Advised the client what can be done for system improvement & business operations.

TECH:

- Informix
- SQL
- Shellscript
- Powerpoint (consulting with Vietnam Bank)

Software Developer

Accenture

Aug 2017 - Nov 2019 (2 years 4 months)

- To support business by analysing the root cause of systems errors and preparing reports.
- Get involved with business and finance side in order to work out a solution.
- Handle all kind of SDLCs tickets, including data patching, program enhancement/rectification, ad hoc reporting etc.
- Develop automate programs to simplify process for SDLCs activities.

Waiter

Mr.mans restaurant

Oct 2015 - Apr 2016 (7 months)

- -Helps to serve foods for customer
- -Provide hospitality and service for the customers
- -Cleaning up the restaurant

Education

🏌 University of Nottingham Malaysia

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Software Engineering 2014 - 2017

Skills

Ad Hoc Analysis • Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) • Business Requirements • Business Analytics • Requirements Gathering • Project Management • Team Management • Analytical Skills • Business Analysis • Requirements Analysis

Honors & Awards



Oct 2022

The award was given when I was serving SG Bank client, voted in confidence by my team members